Hermela Birhanu

+251 929 08 56 41

Hermelabirhanu06@gmail.com

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

April 20, 2023

To: BitApps ICT Solutions PLC

I recently came across the job posting for the QA and system tester position

at your company and I am considering applying for the role. I have a strong

ability to adapt to various environments and possess excellent teamwork

skills. I am confident that I can make a valuable contribution to the team

based on my training and professional experience.

I have 5 years of experience in software related tasks like testing software

and implementing for the clients. Additionally, I have extensive experience

working with various programming languages such as C# and PHP. I am

excited to put my skills to use in helping your business as a tester.

I have attached my complete resume with my experience and qualifications

for QA and system tester.

Thank you for your time and consideration. I look forward to hearing from

you soon.

Sincerely,

Hermela Birhanu

# HERMELA BIRHANU

# **CONTACT INFORMATION**

# Hermelabirhanu@gmail.com

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia (+251) 929 08 56 41 May 24, 1996

Ethiopian

https://Linkdin.com/HermelBi

<u>rhanu</u>

https://github.com/Hermelab1

### **SKILLS**

- Good Communication
   Skill
- Programming Skill
- Problem Solving Skill
- Team work

# Languages

- Amharic | Fluently specks
- English | Good for communications

### **OBJECTIVE**

I am Hermela Birhanu. I hold a BSC degree in computer science with a 2.84 GPA and have been working in software implementation for 5 years. I'm a responsible and energetic individual who excels at working with others to achieve objectives on time and with excellence. I'm skilled at handling multiple tasks on a daily basis and am always eager to learn new skills. I'm particularly interested in pursuing a career as a Quality assurance & system tester and believe that I have the potential to this field.

### **EDUCATION**

# COMPUTER SCIENCE | DEGREE

Admass university Addis Ababa | Jen 2017 - Sep 2021

HARDWARE AND NETWORKING | DIPLOMA

Admass university Addis Ababa | 2012 - 2013

**ALX Software Engineering** 

During my free time, I am enrolled in the ALX software engineering and Data Science online training programs for duration of 12 months. These programs are designed to equip me with the necessary skills and knowledge required to in the field of software engineering and data science.

# Short Term Course

I have been taking some online courses lately. Specifically, I have been learning Python, Front-End Development, Data Science Foundations and Data Analysis.

# HERMELA BIRHANU

## **EXPERIENCE**

# SENIOR SOFTWAREIMPLEMENTER

Professional Electronic Data System PLC (PEDS), Addis Ababa Ethiopia | May 2022 - Present

In my current role, I am responsible for testing software that integrates with third-party software with manually testing a system and also with Postman API testing software. Additionally, I provide clients with the software and assist them with fixing SQL database issues

# IT SUPPORT OFFICER

Professional Electronic Data System PLC (PEDS), Addis Ababa Ethiopia | 2016 – May 2022

Support the customers onsite and over the phone.

# DATA ENCODER

Ethiopian Shipping and Logistics Service Enterprise, Addis Ababa Ethiopia | Aug 2015 – April 2016

Add data to Excel sheets and generate reports.



REF. AU. 15/1787/21

# Temporary Degree

This is to certify that

# HERMELA BRHANU GEBREMARIAM

has graduated from Admas University with Bachelor of Science Degree in

# COMPUTER SCIENCE

On September 18, 2021

This degree has been given pending the issuance of the original degree.

Registrar

2 3 .IAN 2023

Date

President

# Admas University STUDENT RECORD

OFFICE OF THE REGISTRAR
2618 1011553674

0115536745, 0115537677

Degree Awarded Date:

18-Sep-2021

Extension

Major:	Dogico . mai
Computer Science	

Date of Admitssion:   Sex: Female	Math 1011 CoSc 231	CvEt 1022 Stat 1012	CoSc 132 CoSc 269	EnLa 1012 EcEg 122 CoSc 131	CoSc 101 Math 102 EnLa 1011	ID No.	Full Name:
Date of Admission:   2016   Course No.   Course Title	Cumulative Average: Semester: Introduction to Calculus Object-Oriented Programming U	A ade	Cumulative Average: Semester: Structured Programming II Data Communication and Networ Semester Average:	er:	псе	Course Title	Hermela Brhanu Gebremariam
2016  Gr. Course No. Course Title Pt. Semester Average: 6.00 6.00 Math 2052 7.50 11.25 10.50 CoSc 236 10.50 CoSc 232 20 CoSc 232 20 CoSc 232 20 CoSc 232 20 CoSc 236 62.25 Emgster Average: 6.00 Semester Average: 6.00 CoSc 236 CoSc 236 62.25 CoSc 326 Computer Security and Privacy Introduction to Business Wireless Communication and Mob Computing Advanced Database Management Systems 7.50 Semester Average: 7.73.75 CoSc 328 Numerical Methods 8.00 Math 3011 Semester Average: Cumulative Average: Cumulative Average: Cumulative Average: Computing CoSc 328 Numerical Methods Semester Average: Cumulative Average:	2.54 Second sing Java	2017/2018 First 2.30		2.00 Second	016/2017 First 2.00	Dancor	Date of
2016  Gr. Course No. Course Title Pt. Semester Average: 6.00 6.00 Math 2052 7.50 11.25 10.50 CoSc 236 10.50 CoSc 232 20 CoSc 236 62.25 CoSc 326 20 CoSc 326 21 CoSc 326 22 Comulative Average: 21 Computer Security and Privacy Introduction to Business 22 Computing Advanced Database Management Systems 23 Semester Average: 24 Computing CoSc 328 25 Computing CoSc 328 26 Computing Advanced Database Management Systems 26 Computing Computative Average: 27 Computer Security and Privacy Introduction to Business 28 Wireless Communication and Mob Computing Advanced Database Management Systems 29 CoSc 328 20 CoSc 328 21 Computing CoSc 328 22 Computing Computing Computing Computing Computing Computing Advanced Database Management Systems 28 Computer Security and Privacy Introduction to Business 29 Computing CoSc 328 29 CoSc 328 20 CoSc 328 20 CoSc 326 20 Computer Security and Privacy Introduction to Business 20 Computing Computing Computing Computing Advanced Database Management Systems 20 CoSc 328 21 CoSc 328 22 CoSc 328 23 CoSc 326 24 CoSc 326 25 Cumulative Average: 26 Computer Security and Privacy Introduction to Business 26 Computing CoSc 328 27 CoSc 328 28 CoSc 328 29 CoSc 326 20 CoSc	4 4	3 2			w w w	Cr. L	Admissi
2016  Course No.  Course No.  Comulative Average: Semester Average: Semester Average: Semester Average: Semester Average: Cosc 239 Math 2052  Rapid Application Development Discrete Mathematics and Combina Semester Average: Cosc 236 Cosc 232 Cosc 236 Computer Security and Privacy Introduction to Business Wireless Communication and Mob Computing Advanced Database Management Systems Semester Average: Computative Average: Computing Cosc 238 Advanced Database Management Systems Semester Average: Computing Advanced Database Management Systems Semester Average: Cosc 328 Numerical Methods Semester Average: Comulative Average: Cosc 328 Cosc 236 Computing Cosc 328 Cosc 236 Computing Advanced Database Management Systems Semester Average: Computing Advanced Database Management Systems Semester Average: Computing Advanced Database Management Systems Semester Average: Cosc 328 Cosc 328 Cosc 328 Cosc 328 Cosc 366 Computing Advanced Database Management Systems Semester Average: Computative Average: Cosc 328 Cosc 328 Cosc 328 Cosc 326 Cosc 328 Cosc 326 Computing Advanced Database Management Systems Semester Average: Computative Average: Cosc 328 Cosc 328 Cosc 326 Cosc 326 Cosc 326 Computative Average: Cosc 328 Cosc 326 Cosc 326 Computative Average: Cosc 328 Cosc 326 Computative Average: Cosc 328 Cosc 326	вс	φ n	вс		0,00		
Course Title  Semester Average:  Cumulative Average:  Semester:  Rapid Application Development Discrete Mathematics and Combina Semester Average:  Cumulative Average:  Academic Year Semester:  Academic Year Semester:  Academic Year Semester:  Academic Year Semester:  Cumulative Average:  Cumulative Average:  Cumulative Average:  Computer Security and Privacy Introduction to Business Wireless Communication and Mob Computing Advanced Database Management Systems Semester Average:  Cumulative Average:	8.00	4.00 7.50		/n	6.00 6.00 6.00		Female 20
Course Title  Semester Average:  Cumulative Average:  Semester:  Rapid Application Development Discrete Mathematics and Combina Semester Average:  Cumulative Average:  Academic Year Semester:  Academic Year Semester:  Academic Year F Academic Year Semester:  Cumulative Average:  Cumulative Average:  Cumulative Average:  Computer Security and Privacy Introduction to Business Wireless Communication and Mob Computing Advanced Database Management Systems Semester Average:  Cumulative Average:			200	100			)16
Course Title  Semester Average: Semester: Semester: Semester: Semester: Semester: Cumulative Average: Academic Year Semester: Academic Year Semester: Semester: Semester: Semester: Semester: Semester: Semester: Semester: Cumulative Average: Cumulative Average: Semester: Semester: Semester: Semester: Cumulative Average: Cumulative Average: Semester: Cumulative Average: Semester: Cumulative Average:	CoSc 328 Math 3011	CoSc 266	CoSc 366	CoSc 236 CoSc 323 CoSc 242	CoSc 239 Math 2052	Course No.	
	Semester: Summer PC Troubleshooting and Maintenance Numerical Methods Semester Average: 3.00 Cumulative Average: 2.56	Computing Advanced Database Management Systems Semester Average:			Cumulative Average: 2.53  Cumulative Average: 2.53  Semester: Summer Sepid Application Development Discrete Mathematics and Combinatory Semester Average: 3.00	Course Title	Date of Birth:
	a.00	- 1	ယ ယ ယ	ω 4 4 <sup>Δ</sup>	43 3	F 9	May-1
Cr. Hr. 37 37 43 3 3 43 3 3 3 3 3 3 3 3 3 3 3 3	7 1	δ ω					(0)
2	2 4 4		Ç P C	фоо	0 >	Gr.	94 0

Grading System: This record becomes an official transcript only when it bears the seal and signature of the Registrar

A+, A=4 Points; A-=3.75 points; B+=3.50 points; B=3.0 Points; B-=2.75 points; C+=2.50 points; C=2.0 Points; C-=1.75 points; D+=1.50 points; D=1.0 Point; D-1.0 Points; D=1.0 Poin

I=Incomplete; One class hour or 2-3 laboratory hours per week for 16 weeks = on semister hour or credit, \*=Course Repeated; Cr. Hr. =Credit Hour; Lt. Gr. = Grade; Gr. Pt. = =0.75 points; F=0 Points; EX=Exempt Grade Point Average.

Medium of Instruction: English

Pair of Admission:   2016	CoSc 472 CoSc 474 CoSc 265		Acct 101	CoSc 364	CoSc 471	CoSc 466	CoSc 256			CoSc 382	CoSc 461	CoSc 441			CoSc 475	CoSc 348	CoSc 465	CoSc 413			CoSc 368	CoSc 431	CoSc 343	CoSc 333			Course No.	ID No.	Parameter Manager
Gr.  Course No.  Course No.  Course Title  BMgt 3081  Entrepreneurship & Small Busines  Management  Semior Project  Semester Average:  CoSc 221  CoSc 221  Compulative Average:  Gumulative Average:  Computer Organization and Archi  Semester Average:  Computer Organization and Archi  Semester Average:  Comulative Average:	semester: Sec atabase Systems			Information Storage and Retrieval	Formal Language Theory	Computer Graphics	Academic Year 2020/2021 Semester: First Introduction to Artificial Intelligence		rerage:	Industrial Practice	E-Commerce			37	Simulation and Modeling	Object-Oriented Software Engineering	Multimedia Systems	mester:			System & Network Administration	Advanced Programming in UNIX	Software Engineering	Internet and Website Development	M En		Course Title		
Gr.  Course No.  Course No.  Course Title  BMgt 3081  Entrepreneurship & Small Busines  Management  Semior Project  Semester Average:  CoSc 221  CoSc 221  Compulative Average:  Gumulative Average:  Computer Organization and Archi  Semester Average:  Computer Organization and Archi  Semester Average:  Comulative Average:		121	3	ω	ω	ω	ω		6	(L)	ω	ω		97	W	ω	(L)	ω		85	ω	ω	ü	44		Hr.		of Admi:	
Course No.  Course No.  Course Title  Entrepreneurship & Small Busines  Management Semester Average: Computer Organization and Arch Semester Average: Cumulative Average:	> B Ç		Ç	0	ç	A	φ			A	Þ	ç			0	Ç	В	B+			B.	В	Þ	>		Gr.	Ľ.	SSION:	
Entrepreneurship & Small Busines  BMgt 3081 Entrepreneurship & Small Busines  Management Senior Project Semester Average: Cosc 221 Computer Organization and Arch Semester Average: Computer Organization and Arch Semester Average: Academic Year Semester: Introduction to Logic Semester Average: Condition of Logic Computer Organization and Arch Semester Average:	7.50 9.00	335.00	7.50	6.00	7.50	12.00	8.25		293.75	12.00	12.00	7.50		262.25	6.00	7.50	9.00	10.50		229.25	8.25	9.00	12.00	16.00		Pt.			
Course Title  Entrepreneurship & Small Busines Management Senior Project Semester Average: Cumulative Average: Cumulative Average: Cumulative Average: Academic Year Semester: Introduction to Logic Semester Average: Cumulative Average: Cumulative Average:		9					Pop	Style Das (	in in	· CC 8.5	201				1012	050	*			CoSc 221			400 0000	CoSc 488	BMgt 3081	V. Ont se 140.			
Marie Maria							is it				4,		Cumulauve Average.	Cumulative Average:	Semester Average	mester:			Semester Average:	Semester: Sun Computer Organization and Architectu				Management Senior Project	Entrepreneurship & Small Business	Course Little	1		
					_	_				_	_			43	-	_			6	ω		7	t	200	8		7		Section forms
143																110			- 1				1						0

Grading System: This record becomes an official transcript only when it bears the scal and signature of the Registrar

A+, A=4 Points; A-=3.75 points; B+=3.50 points; B=3.0 Points; B-=2.75 points; C+=2.50 points; C=2.0 Points; C-=1.75 points; D+=1.50 points; D-1.0 Points; D
A+, A=4 Points; A-=3.75 points; B+=3.50 points; B=3.0 Points; B-=2.75 points; C+=2.50 points; C-=2.0 Points; C-=1.75 points; D+=1.50 points; D-1.0 Points; D
A+, A=4 Points; A-=3.75 points; B+=3.50 points; B-3.0 Points; B-=2.75 points; C+=2.50 points; C-=2.0 Points; C-=1.75 points; D-1.0 Points; D =0.75 points; F=0 Points; EX=Exempt

I=Incomplete; One class hour or 2-3 laboratory hours per week for 16 weeks = on semister hour or credit,\*=Course Repeated; Cr. Hr. =Credit Hour; Lt. Gr. = Grade; Gr. Pt. = Grade Point Average. Medium of Instruction: English

	Course No.	Full Name: ID No.
*	course Title	ne: Hermela Brhanu Gebremariam ADOL/0859/16
		mariam Sex:  Date of Admission:
Sedinas dens	Cr. Lt. Hr. Gr.	Admiss
That dens		
Mile Dy	Gr. Pt.	Female
24 1 281 -28-18 1 2 3 3 3		ale 2016
Total Hours: Total Grade Cumulative / Major GPA: Status: 12-3 JAN 2023 Date of Issue	Course No.	
Total Hours:  Total Grade Points:  Cumulative Average:  Major GPA:  Status:  AN 2023  ate of Issue	Course Title	Date
Name of Registrar	Cr. Lt. Hr. Gr.	Date of Birth: 24-May-1994 G.C.
, a	Pt. Cr.	G.C

Grading System: This record becomes an official transcript only when it bears the seal and signature of the Registrar

A+, A=4 Points; A-=3.75 points; B+=3.50 points; B=3.0 Points; B=2.75 points; C+=2.50 points; C=2.0 Points; C-=1.75 points; D+=1.50 points; D=1.0 Point; D-=2.75 points; D=1.0 Poi

=0.75 points; F=0 Points; EX=Exempt

Medium of Instruction: English

Grade Point Average. I=Incomplete; One class hour or 2-3 laboratory hours per week for 16 weeks = on semister hour or credit,\*=Course Repeated; Cr. Hr. =Credit Hour; Lt. Gr. = Grade; Gr. Pt. =